Guide to the Southgate-Jones Family Papers, 1760-2008 RL.01199
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Pictures Series, 1805-1940 and undated (bulk undated).
  - Watercolors and sketches, Mattie Southgate Jones and Anonymous, undated (Box 39)
  - Lantern slides, Durham, 191120 envelopes) (Box 40)
- Oversize Material
  - Correspondence Series
    - Correspondence, 1794 (Box 50)
  - North Carolina Joint Stock Land Bank of Durham Series
    - Financial Papers, 1929-1933 and undated (Box 50)
    - Reports, 1929-1933 and undated (Box 50)
  - Business Records Series
    - 1873-1909 and undated (Box 50)
    - Volumes
      - Alphabetical:
        - Columbus Insurance and Banking Co., Abstract of policies, 1879-1889. (Volume 1)
        - J. Southgate and Son, Letterbook, 1882-1883. (Volume 2)
        - J. Southgate and Son, Record of payments, 1887-1906. (Volume 3)
        - J. Southgate and Son, Policy Register, 1909-1914. (Volume 4)
        - J. Southgate and Son, Record of payments, 1910-1913. (Volume 5)
        - J. Southgate and Son, Abstract of policies, 1911-1914. (Volume 6)
        - J. Southgate and Son, Account book, 1911-1916. (Volume 7)
        - J. Southgate and Son, Account book, 1911-1917. (Volume 8)
        - New England Fire Insurance Co. of Providence, R.I., Policy Register, 1911-1912. (Volume 9)
        - Southgate Jones and Co. Real Estate, Account book, 1912-1914. (Volume 10)
        - Standard Mutual Life Insurance Co., Inc., Scrapbook, 1908. (Volume 11)
        - Standard Mutual Life Insurance Co., Inc., Record of payments, 1908-1911. (Volume 12)
        - Standard Mutual Life Insurance Co., Inc., Record of payments, 1908-1912. (Volume 13)
        - Standard Mutual Life Insurance Co., Inc., Record of disbursements, 1908-1912. (Volume 14)
        - Standard Mutual Life Insurance Co., Inc., Application register, 1909-1913. (Volume 15)
        - Standard Mutual Life Insurance Co., Inc., Policy Register #1, 1909-1911. (Volume 16)
        - Standard Mutual Life Insurance Co., Inc., Policy Register #2, 1910-1911. (Volume 17)
        - Standard Mutual Life Insurance Co., Inc., Account book, 1911. (Volume 18)
        - Standard Mutual Life Insurance Co., Inc., Policy Register, undated (Volume 19)
        - Star Fire Insurance Co. of New York, Record of accounts and payments, 1882-1883. (Volume 20)
      - Chronological:
        - 1887-1897, (Record of accounts and payments) (Volume 21)
        - 1908-1910, (Policy Register) (Volume 22)
        - 1908-1912, (Account books) (Volume 23-24)
        - 1910-1911, (Promotion lists) (Volume 25)
        - 1910-1912, (Orders for Byrd Knotters) (Volume 26)
        - 1912-1915, (Account book) (Volume 27)
        - 1912-1915, (Account book) (Volume 28)
        - 1914-1916, (Account book) (Volume 29)
        - 1914-1917, (Account book) (Volume 30)
        - undated, (Index of names) (Volume 31)
        - undated, (Policy expirations) (Volume 32)
  - Legal Papers Series
    - 1783-1951 (Box 50)
  - Financial Papers Series
    - 1863 (Box 50)
    - Volume, personal finances, unidentified, 1901-1902 (Box 50)
  - Genealogy Series
    - undated (Oversize-folder 1)
    - 1909-1927 and undated (Oversize-folder 2)
    - undated (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous Series
    - 1921-1939 and undated (Oversize-folder 2)
    - 1906-1918 and undated (Box 50)
  - Clippings Series
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 49)
    - Scrapbook, 1922-1935 and undated (Box 50)
  - Printed Materials Series
    - 1885-1940 and undated (Box 50)
  - Pictures Series
    - Photograph album fragments, 1908 and undated (Box 49)
    - Loose pictures, undated (Box 49)
- Accession (2009-0020), 1910s-1990s, 6 boxes
  Addition (2009-0020) (1800 items; 4 lin. ft.; dated 1910s-1990s and no date) contains materials from the Southgate Jones Jr.'s involvement in the Durham revitalization project (1950s), the United Fund of Durham (1960s-1990s), and the family's ownership of a molybdenum mine in North Carolina (1950s-1970s). Also included are fire insurance records (organized by Durham street, 1960s-1970s), three large maps of the molybdenum mine area, and a scrapbook celebrating J. Southgate and Son Inc.'s 75th anniversary of business in 1947.
  - United Fund of Durham materials (Box 41)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 41)
  - Molybdenum mine materials (Box 42)
  - J. Southgate and Son Inc. 75th Anniversary scrapbook, 1947 (Box 43)
  - North Carolina Molybdenum Corporation Inc. 1943 metal seal (Box 43)
  - Fire insurance catalog cards, A-E (Box 44)
  - Fire insurance catalog cards, W. Main St.-Swift Ave. (Box 45)
  - Molybdenum mine area maps (3) (Box 46)
  - Panoramic group photographs from the National Association of Insurance Agents conferences (Oversize-folder 1)
    - NAIA, Signal Mountain, Chattanooga, Tennessee, March 14-16, 1922. Photographer: McMayberry (Box 46)
    - NAIA, Boston, September 12, 1916 (Box 46)
    - NAIA, Mid-year conference, Mt. Vernon, Virginia, February 16, 1917. Photographer: Schultz (Box 46)
    - NAIA, 20th Annual convention, Asheville, North Carolina, July 12, 1917. Photographer: McCanless (Box 46)
    - Unlabeled group photograph at a beach (Box 46)
- Accession (2010-0086), 1896-2008, 1 box
  Accession (2010-0086) (5 items; 2.0 lin. ft.; dated 1896-2008) includes scrapbooks from the political and insurance career of James H. Southgate, dated 1896-1916; typed and handwritten versions of Southgate Jones' autobiography; and a spiral bound volume containing the autobiography of Southgate Jones Jr., dated 2008.
  - Bound copy of Southgate Jones Jr.'s autobiography, In the Presence of the Past, 2008 (Box 47)
  - Typed and holograph copies of Southgate Jones' autobiography, date unknown (Box 47)
  - 2 scrapbooks from the career of James H. Southgate, 1896-1916 (Box 47)
- Accession (2011-0091), 1920-1950, 1 box
  Accession (2011-0091) (1 item, 0.2 lin. ft.; between 1920-1950) is a early- to mid-twentieth century cookbook owned by Mrs. Mattie Logan Southgate Jones, comprising handwritten recipes, many obtained from family members and friends.
  - Cookbook pages (Box 48)
  - Cookbook binder (Box 48)